inc.in 2019-04-21

# Indian National Congress

### Thank you for visiting the website of Indian National Congress (Site)

The Privacy Policy is applicable to the websites of Indian National Congress. This privacy statement also does not apply to the websites of our partners, affiliates, agents or to any other third parties, even if their websites are linked to Site. We recommend you review the privacy statements of the other parties with whom you interact.

For the purposes of this privacy policy, "affiliates " means any entity or project or  venture that is wholly or partially owned or controlled by Indian  National Congress. "agents" means any subcontractor, vendor or other entity with whom we have an ongoing business relationship to provide products, services, or information.  
The following terms governs the collection, use and protection of your personal Information by the Site. This Privacy Policy shall be applicable to users who visit the Site. By visiting and/ or using the Site you have agreed to the following Privacy Policy.

### Introduction:

As a registered member of the Site and/or as a visitor (if applicable and as the case may be), you will to get an insight on the updates and detailed information of the happenings and developments within and by the organisation. In addition, look forward to receiving monthly newsletters and updates from the Indian National congress.

That's why we've provided this Privacy Policy, which sets forth our policies regarding the collection, use and protection of the Personal Information of those using or visiting the Site.

### Personal Information

Personal Information means and includes all information that can be linked to a specific individual or to identify any individual, such as name, address, mailing address, telephone number, e - mail address, aadhar number, constituency, voter details, credit card number, cardholder name, expiration date, information about the constituency, and any and all details that may be requested while any user visits or uses the website

When you browse the Website, Indian National Congress  may collect information regarding the domain and host from which you access the Internet, the Internet Protocol address of the computer or Internet Service Provider you are using, and anonymous site statistical data. The Website uses cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. Personal Information will not be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that we do not sell or rent our users' Personal Information to third parties.

Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version. Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the privacy practices described to you in this Privacy Policy at the time you provided us with your Personal Information.  
Information we collect from you?

When browsing our Website, you are not required to provide any Personal Information unless and until you choose to sign up for one of our e-mail newsletters or other services as is described in the Website from time to time.

Making a donation, submitting your blog/website link

In order to make a donation  through our Website, you may provide us with certain Personal Information such as your name, address, cheque or credit card number (including expiration date, credit card billing address) as and how applicable , telephone number, e - mail address and the link to your website or blog you wish to submit. We may also ask you for other Personal Information, such as your constituency name and any other such detail. We may require this information to keep a record of the donations made to Indian National Congress.

### Registration

If you choose to become a member of Indian National Congress, you may be required to provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address. Wherein if at any time you chose to accept to become a member of the website in addition to the information before stated you will also be required to provide a unique login name, password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including but not limited to:

  * Personal identification
  * To customize the content of our site to strive to meet your specific needs; and/or
  * To make product or other improvements to our site. In addition, we need your e - mail address to confirm your new member registration. As a Website member you will also occasionally receive updates from us about Indian National Congress’ activities in your area, new Website services, and other noteworthy items. However, you may choose at any time to no longer receive these types of e - mail messages. Please see our Opt - Out Policy described below for details.

###  Online Surveys

Indian National Congress values opinions and comments from users, so we may conduct online surveys. Participation in these surveys is entirely optional. Typically, the information is aggregated, and used to make improvements to the Website and its services and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for Website users. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey.

###  Automatic Logging of Session Data

We automatically log generic information about your computer's connection to the Internet, which we call "session data", that is anonymous and not linked to any Personal Information. Session data consists of things such as IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the user while on the Website. An IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the Website the user wishes to view. We collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the Website, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the Website, how long visitors to the Website are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. Although such information does not identify any visitor personally, it is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor's Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.

###  Cookies

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. There are many myths circulating about cookies, but you should know that cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses or harvest your Personal Information. The use of cookies is very common on the Internet and Indian National Congress' use of cookies is similar to that of such Websites as any other reputable online portal.

First and foremost, you can rest assured that no personally identifiable information ("PII") about you (e.g., name, address, etc.) is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by the Website and, as a result, none can be passed on to any third parties.

Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our Website. Indian National Congress may use cookies to personalize your experience on the Website as these types of cookies allow you to log in without having to type your log - in name each time (only your password is needed. None of this information is passed to any third party, and is used solely by us to provide you with a better user experience on the Website.

A cookie may also be placed by our advertising server. Such cookies are used only for purposes of tracking the effectiveness of advertising served by us on our Website and no PII is gathered from you by the use of these cookies, nor is this information shared with any third parties. Similarly, a cookie may be placed by our third - party advertising companies or advertisement providers or servers. These companies may use aggregated statistics about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide information and updates about the happenings on the Website that you may be interested in or any subject of potential interest to you. The information they collect does not include your PII.

The third - party advertising companies or advertisement providers may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. Any such information is anonymous. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide information and updates about the happenings on the Website that may interests you. No PII is collected during this process. The information is anonymous, and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. 

Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies. Of course, by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. Indian National Congress supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking Indian National congress’ cookies may disable certain features on the Website, and may make it impossible to use certain services available on the Website. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain websites while permitting cookies from websites you trust, like Indian National congress’ Website.

### Other

From time to time we may add or enhance services available on the Website. To the extent these services are provided, and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilitate the service requested. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use your email address, name, nature of the question, etc. to respond to your question. We may also store such information to assist us in making the Website the better and easier to use.

**With whom we may share your Personal Information?**

For making the use of Website effective and  resourceful Indian National Congress may share your information with  vendors, consultants, and other service providers or volunteers who are engaged by or working with us and who need access to such information to carry out their work for us; with candidates, organizations, groups or causes that we believe have similar political viewpoints, principles or objectives; to report required information to the Elections Commission of India ,or any other statutory body at any time as may be required. ;when you give us your consent to do so, including if we notify you on the Website, that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner and you provide such information; when we believe in good faith that we are required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of Indian National Congress or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, agents or office bearers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities.; to enforce or apply this Policy, our Terms of Usage, or our other policies or agreements; and in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, reorganization, acquisition, asset sale, financing or lending transaction or in any other situation where personal information may be disclosed or transferred as one of the assets of the Indian National Congress.

**How can you opt out of from our website and informational updates?**

You may "opt out" of receiving text messages, email updates and newsletters by following the instructions in those text messages and emails. Please note that we may still send you other types of emails, such as emails about your use of our Sites, or use information as otherwise described in this Policy, even if you opt out of receiving email updates and newsletters. Changes to information in your account does not affect information provided to others as set forth in this policy, including in connection with petitions or donations or that has been previously shared with like-minded candidates, organizations, groups or causes 

**What safeguards we have in place to protect your Personal Information?**

We take reasonable measures to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Please be aware, however, that despite our efforts, no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no method of data transmission that can be guaranteed against any interception or other type of misuse. To protect the confidentiality of personal information, you must keep your password confidential and not disclose it to any other person. You are responsible for all uses of our web sites by any person using your password. Please advise us immediately if you believe your password has been misused.

**Does this policy apply to third party links on Website?**

Our website may contain links to other websites. Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. This Policy does not apply to such linked sites, and we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of these websites or any other sites that are linked to from our Sites. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information. 

This policy is effective as of (date). Any material changes in the way Indian National Congress  uses Personal Information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices via email to (emailid). Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. Indian National Congress  will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries at the earliest.

**Thank you for using the Website!**
